

Vinit Nair Senior DevOps/Software Engineer

B104, Swastik Enclave, Brahmand, Azadnagar, Thane,

I am a talented and enthusiastic individual with more than 4 years of Industrial experience. I am currently seeking a Senior DevOps/Automation Engineer position to take my career to the next level.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior DevOps/Automation Engineer Larsen & Toubro Infotech Limited

09/2019 - Present

Navi Mumbai

Role & Contribution

- Designing an end to end architecture and migrating current monolithic applications to the Microservices architecture
- Tools used: Jenkins, Kubernetes, Docker, Nexus Repository Manager, Gitlab, Zabbix, Ansible, Apache Kafka

DevOps Engineer Reliance Industries Limited

05/2017 - 09/2019 Role & Contribution Navi Mumbai

- Automated the deployment process with approvals across multiple environments using Jenkins and containerized the entire components with Kubernetes and Docker Swarm. Achieved Autoscaling and near 0 downtime deployment for all the containers/pods.
- Tools used: Jenkins, Docker, Docker Swarm, Kubernetes, Nexus Repository Manager, Gitlab, Zabbix, Ansible, Apache Kafka

Jr SQL DBA/DevOps Engineer R M Parkar HR Management Services

04/2016 - 01/2017

Mumbai

- Achievements/Tasks
- Successfully completed an Open source project to digitize timesheet entry for employees of RM Parkar HR Management Services.
- Tools used: Jenkins, Docker, Docker Swarm, Nexus Repository Manager, Gitlab

Intern

Reliance Industries Limited

05/2014 - 07/2014

Achievements/Tasks

Worked on tools like ELN & LIMS

Navi Mumbai

EDUCATION

BS Computer Science

California State University, Fresno, CA, US

08/2012 - 12/2015

3.13/4.0

SKILLS

Docker Docker Swarm Kubernetes **Jenkins** Nexus Repository Manager Apache Kafka Zabbix Ansible Microsoft Azure **AWS** MS Office

CERTIFICATIONS

Docker Certified Associate - Docker Inc (10/2019 - 10/2021)

Microsoft Certified Professional in Administering SQL 2012 Servers (02/2016 - Present)

ACCP Pro - Aptech Certified Computer Professional (07/2014 - Present)

Dale Carnegie Professional Communication - Dale Carnegie (02/2014 – Present)

LANGUAGES

Full Professional Proficiency

Hindi

Full Professional Proficiency

Marathi

Full Professional Proficiency

Malayalam

Full Professional Proficiency

INTERESTS

Chess

Cricket

Listening to Songs